<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DSSG Berlin</title>
    <link>https://dssg-berlin.org/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DSSG Berlin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution Share Alike 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 15:58:46 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dssg-berlin.org/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Datenanalyse für den guten Zweck</title>
      <link>https://dssg-berlin.org/en/blog/datenanalyse-fuer-den-guten-zweck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 15:58:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dssg-berlin.org/en/blog/datenanalyse-fuer-den-guten-zweck/</guid>
      <description>Data Science for Social Good Berlin unterstützt soziale Organisationen bei ihrer Arbeit mithilfe von &amp;quot;Data Science&amp;quot;. Uns fällt dabei immer wieder auf, dass soziale Organisationen zwar Begriffe wie &amp;quot;Künstliche Intelligenz&amp;quot;(KI), &amp;quot;Big Data&amp;quot; und &amp;quot;Data Science&amp;quot; kennen und schon einzelne Beispiele gesehen haben. Es fehlt ihnen aber oft an Orientierung, für welche Arten von Problemen Data-Science-Methoden geeignet sind.
Darum haben wir die Vielzahl an Beispielen, die es bereits gibt, anhand der Problemarten kategorisiert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://dssg-berlin.org/en/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dssg-berlin.org/en/glossary/</guid>
      <description>Data Science ist das Ableiten von Erkenntnissen aus Daten. […] Es werden Techniken und Theorien aus vielen Bereichen der Mathematik, Statistik, Informatik, Maschinellem Lernen […] verwendet, aus denen praxisnahe und benutzerfreundliche Vorhersagemodelle und Visualisierungen entwickelt werden. (http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_science)
Data Scientists (DatenanalystInnen) nutzen ihre Datenverarbeitungs- und Analysekenntnisse um reichhaltige Datenquellen zu erschließen und zu interpretieren. […] Sie produzieren Visualisierungen die dabei helfen, Daten zu verstehen, und mathematische Vorhersagemodelle um aus den Daten wirkungsorientierte Entscheidungen abzuleiten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imprint</title>
      <link>https://dssg-berlin.org/en/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dssg-berlin.org/en/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Privacy We make the following promises about your personal information as a user of the site:
When you correspond with DSSG Berlin via our email address, or sign up for our newsletter, we keep your contact information stored for use by the DSSG organising team.
We may use your email address to contact you about your use of the site (for example, to ask for feedback) or with occasional announcements about our activities, via our newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteer</title>
      <link>https://dssg-berlin.org/en/volunteer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dssg-berlin.org/en/volunteer/</guid>
      <description>Being a volunteer with DSSG Whether you’re a great data scientist, or a great organiser, your contribution makes a difference. Volunteer either directly at DSSG or at our NGO-focused events that we organize in Berlin: Data Science Speed Dating, Impact Mapping Workshops, Office Hours and Datathons. Check our blog https://blog.dssg-berlin.org/ for more information about past events, projects and NGOs we’ve worked with.
Become a volunteer Please send an email to volunteer@dssg-berlin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work with us / Submit a project</title>
      <link>https://dssg-berlin.org/en/apply/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dssg-berlin.org/en/apply/</guid>
      <description>We help NGOs to make use of their data by connecting them with volunteer data scientists and analysts.
 Learn how to use data effectively Find out how to use data science to your benefit Realise a project with the support of our network  Where we can support    Understand target groups
    Automation of manual processes
    Analysis/prediction of demand</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>